Guide to the University of Pittsburgh Archives Audio Recordings Collection, 1950-2000 UA.Audio
ULS Archives & Special Collections
University of Pittsburgh Archives Audio Recordings Collection
1950-2000
ULS Archives & Special Collections
University of Pittsburgh. Archives Service Center
UA.Audio
381 items
A collection of audio recordings pertaining to the University of Pittsburgh and its history dating from ca. 1950 to 2005.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
The collection contains open reel tape and standard audiocassettes. An open reel player and cassette player are required to access content which the Archives Service Center can provide.
Previous Citation
University of Pittsburgh Archives Audio Recordings, 1950-2005, UA.Audio, University Archives, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Arrangement
The collection of audio recordings are arranged into the following nine series:
Series I. University Events
Series II. University History
Series III. Administration
Series IV. Student Life
Series V. Media Events
Series VI. Lectures
Series VII. Research Findings
Series VIII. International Events
Series IX. Assorted
Scope and Content Notes
This collection contains audio recordings pertaining to the University of Pittsburgh and its history dating from ca. 1950 to 2005. Content available includes Commencement proceedings, interviews with University chancellors, lectures, and student life. The dominant media types are open reel tapes and standard audiocassettes.
Acquisition Information
This collection was acquired over a period of years from deposits by University Offices.
Research -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Education; Research institutes -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Interviews; University of Pittsburgh; Memorials -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Universities and colleges -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Commencement ceremonies -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Student activities -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Audiotapes; Audiocassettes; University of Pittsburgh
- University Events, 1950-1994; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This series contains audio items focused on University-sponsored events, such as commencements, convocations, facility groundbreakings, guest lecturers and memorial events from throughout the second half of the twentieth century.
  - Commencements, 1959-1994; 1.
    This subseries contains 19 audio recordings of commencement proceedings and speeches from 1959-1994. Highlights include speeches given by former Representative F. Bradford Morse and Edward A. Weeks, editor of The Atlantic Monthly.
    - University Commencement- Speaker- Edward A. Weeks, June 10, 1959; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 15, Reel 179)
    - Commencement- Week Seminars on Automation, June 1961; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 3, Reel 16)
    - University Commencement- Speaker- Wesley W. Posvar, April 27, 1969; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 7, Reel 62)
    - Commencement Address (Law and Health Professions) - Speaker - William Hoffman Stewart, May 29, 1969; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 15, Reel 172)
    - University Commencement- Speaker- F. Bradford Morse, April 28, 1973; 2 reel-to-reel 5" (Box 8, Reel 70)
    - Commencement Address- Speaker- Zbigniew Brzezinski, April 28, 1974; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 9, Cassette 73)
    - Commencement Address- Speaker- Dr. James Hester, April 1975; 1 cassette_tape (Box 9, Cassette 76)
    - Commencement Program with Music, April 26, 1981; 1 cassette_tape (Box 12, Cassette 138)
    - Commencement Program, April 25, 1982; 3 cassette_tapes (Box 12, Cassette 139)
    - University Commencement, April 26, 1983; 3 cassette_tapes (Box 24, Cassette 269)
    - University Commencement, 1983; 3 reel-to-reel (Box 16, Reel 181-183)
    - University Commencement, 1985; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 16, Cassette 187)
    - University Commencement, May 10, 1987; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 27, Cassette 283)
    - University Commencement, April 30, 1989; 5 cassette_tapes (Box 27, Cassette 288)
    - University Commencement, April 28, 1990; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 28, Cassette 298)
    - University Commencement -Speaker Clark Kerr, April 28, 1991 (Box 30, Cassette 376)
    - University Commencement, April 26, 1992; 3 cassette_tapes (Box 29, Cassette 353)
    - University Commencement, May 1, 1993; 3 cassette_tapes (Box 28, Cassette 310)
    - University Commencement, May 2, 1994; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 28, Cassette 319)
    - University Commencement -Speaker Sheldon Hackney, April 28, 1996 (Box 30, Cassette 377)
    - University Commencement -Speaker Paul O'Neill, April 27, 2003 (Box 30, Cassette 382)
    - University Commencement- Speaker Sam B. Gould, 1970; 1 cassette_tape (Box 19, Cassette 211)
    - University Commencement- Speaker- Wesley W. Posvar, April 1984
    - University Commencement- Speaker- Richard C. Atkinson, April 22, 1979
    - University Commencement- Speaker- William Coleman, April 25, 1975
    - Commencement, April 24, 1975 (April 24, 1977)
    - Commencement - Speaker - Dean Waldo Mallot, June 11, 1958
    - Commencement- "Break the Silence Vietnam" -Speaker - Robert Colodny, April 4, 1969
    - University Lectures, 1950-1989; 4.
      This subseries contains 23 audio recordings of University-sponsored lectures from 1950-1989. Contained within are mainly lectures given by visiting researchers and academics. Highlights of this subseries include a lecture by Louis Farrakhan as well as a lecture series on brainwashing during the Korean War.
      - "The Life of Robert Burns" - Conducted by F.B. Snyder, Febraury 17, 1950; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 4, Reel 26)
      - "Folktales in the Revival of Norwegian Nationalism" - Conducted by Henning Larsen, March 3, 1950; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 5, Reel 32)
      - Library Lectures, 1955; 2 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 19, Reel 207)
      - Library Lectures - Conducted by Lorena Garloch, Harriet Laubach, Helen J. Moore, October 1954-October 1959; 12 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 1, Reel 2)
      - Vietnam Pitt Teach-In, 1967; 3 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 1, Reel 19)
      - "The State of Special Collections at the University of Pittsburgh" - Conducted by Ruth Salisbury, October 29, 1970; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 1, Reel 21)
      - Heinz Lecture, 1982; 1 cassette_tape (Box 16, Cassette 189)
      - Farrakhan Lecture - Conducted by Louis Farrakhan, November 13, 1985; 3 cassette_tapes (Box 16, Cassette 190)
      - Heinz Lecture and Press Interview - Conducted by Helmut Schmidt, February 28, 1986; 4 cassette_tapes (Box 16, Cassette 191)
      - Bob Wolke Log Cabin Presentation - Conducted by Bob Wolke, August 27, 1987; 1 cassette_tape (Box 27, Cassette 284)
      - "Give Us Back Our Good Name: Media, Ethics, and Character" - Conducted by Martin Walker, October 7, 1987; 1 cassette_tape (Box 29, Cassette 349)
      - Ethics Symposium: The Honor Code at West Point, 1988-1989; 1 cassette_tape (Box 28, Cassette 294)
      - "A Generation of Indian Warfare in Western Pennsylvania" - Conducted by H.G. Cleland, undated; 1 reel-to-reel 7"; 2 cassette tapes (Box 4, Item 27)
      - "Arabic Literature" - Conducted by P.K. Hitti, undated; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 4, Reel 29)
      - "Labor Costs and Small Business" - Conducted by Jules Backman, undated; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 4, Reel 25)
      - "Karl Marx: His Life and Philosophy" - Unknown Lecturer, 1956; 2 reel-to-reel 7"; 1 cassette tape (Box 5, Item 37)
      - "Informal Lecture on the Subject of History" - Conducted by Alfred Proctor James, undated; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 5, Reel 30)
      - "The Essential Quality of Polish Literature" - Conducted by Edmund Zawacki, undated; 1 reel-to-reel 7"; 1 cassette tape (Box 6, Item 51)
      - "Dynamics of a Free and Responsible Society" - Conducted by Dr. Milton Esman, undated; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 21, Reel 227)
      - "Brainwashing: On Results of Inquiry about Prison Camp Behavior of US Soldiers in Korea" - Conducted by Maj. Dr. William E. Mayer, undated; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 23, Reel 251)
      - "Brainwashing: Psycho-Cultural Characteristics Found in American POW's" - Conducted by Maj. Dr. William E. Mayer, undated; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 24, Reel 260)
      - GSPIA Tape #43 - "Utilities and Limitations of Behavioral Analysis in International Affairs" - Conducted by Karl Deutsch, undated; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 24, Reel 267)
      - "Pittsburgh in the Revolutionary Years/A Generation of Indian Warfare in W. Pennsylvania" - Conducted by Hugh Gregg Cleland, undated; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 1, Cassette 7)
  - Convocations, 1958-1997; 2.
    This subseries contains 14 audio recordings of University convocation proceedings spanning the years 1958-1989. Highlights of the subseries include speeches given by former Supreme Court Chief Justice Earl Warren and Pulitzer Prize winning Librarian of Congress, Archibald MacLeish.
    - Honors Convocation - Speaker, Chancellor Edward Litchfield, October 29, 1958; 2 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 7, Reel 54)
    - Honors Convocation - Speaker - Archibald MacLeish, 1959; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 17, Reel 194)
    - Honors Convocation - Speaker - Pearl Buck, 1960; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 17, Reel 195)
    - Honors Convocation - Speaker - Earl Warren, 1961; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 17, Reel 199)
    - Honors Convocation - Speaker - Edward Teller, 1963; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 17, Reel 198)
    - Honors Convocation - Speaker - Charlie Snow, 1964; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 17, Reel 196)
    - Honors Convocation - Speaker - Dr. Norman A. Graebner, 1981; 1 reel-to-reel 7"; 2 cassette tapes (Box 16, Item 184)
    - Honors Convocation - Speaker - Robert Frost, July 1958; 1 reel-to-reel 7"; 1 cassette tape (Box 17, Reel 193)
    - Honors Convocation, 1982; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 16, Reel 185)
    - Honors Convocation, 1984; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 16, Reel 186)
    - Honors Convocation, 1987; 1 cassette_tape (Box 28, Cassette 299)
    - Honors Convocation, March 17, 1987; 1 cassette_tape (Box 28, Cassette 281)
    - Honors Convocation, 1988; 1 cassette_tape (Box 28, Cassette 300)
    - Honors Convocation, 1989; 1 cassette_tape (Box 28, Cassette 301)
    - Honors Convocation, Speaker, Louis W. Sullivan, March 13, 1991 (Box 30, Cassette 378)
    - Honors Convocation, Speaker, Donald M. Henderson, March 13, 1994 (Box 30, Cassette 379)
    - Honors Convocation, Speaker, Rev. Edward A. Malloy, February 28, 1995 (Box 30, Cassette 380)
    - Honors Convocation, February 28, 1997
      Investiture of Mark A. Nordenberg, Speakers: Richard L. Ferguson and William E. Strickland Jr.
  - Dedications/Groundbreakings, 1956-1992; 3.
    This subseries contains 16 audio recordings of dedications or groundbreakings of the University of Pittsburgh's landmarks and facilities from 1956-1992. Highlights include groundbreaking ceremonies for the Law School as well as the dedication of notable buildings, such as the Cathedral of Learning.
    - Dedication of Cathedral of Learning - Speaker - Chancellor John G. Bowman, March 8, 1956; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 1, Cassette 3)
    - Dedication of Cathedral of Learning - Speaker - John G. Bowman, March 8, 1956; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 15, Reel 173)
    - Dedication of David L. Lawrence Hall, June 17, 1971; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 7, Reel 57)
    - Dedication of Mervis Hall, October 8, 1972; 1 reel-to-reel 5" (Box 8, Reel 64)
    - Key Presentation - New Science Facility, January 31, 1974; 1 cassette_tape (Box 11, Cassette 91)
    - Central Field Plaza Dedication, November 11, 1974; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 11, Reel 98)
    - Dedication of Tryon Library, May 16, 1976; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 11, Reel 96)
    - Cathedral Slate Dedication, June 15, 1976; 1 cassette_tape (Box 11, Cassette 111)
    - Judge Horner Brown Dedication, March 3, 1978; 3 cassette_tapes (Box 11, Cassette 119)
    - Law School Groundbreaking Ceremony, November 3, 1973; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 8, Reel 67)
    - Victoria Building Dedication Ceremony, October 18, 1978; 1 cassette_tape (Box 12, Cassette 130)
    - Forbes Quadrangle Dedication Ceremony, October 19, 1978; 1 cassette_tape (Box 12, Cassette 131)
    - Forbes Residence Hall Dedication Ceremony, October 20, 1978; 1 cassette_tape (Box 12, Cassette 132)
    - Dedication of Croghan-Schenley Room, February 1982; 1 cassette_tape (Box 12, Cassette 137)
    - Sutherland Hall Dedication Ceremony, September 2, 1992; 1 cassette_tape (Box 28, Cassette 311)
    - Dedication of Langley Aerodome, undated; 1 cassette_tape (Box 12, Cassette 135)
    - WPU Grand Opening Dedication, September 7, 1983
  - Memorial Events, 1974-1992; 5.
    This subseries contains 14 audio recordings of memorial events dedicated to members of the University of Pittsburgh faculty or important figures within the City of Pittsburgh from 1974-1992. Notable entries include the Samuel Lazerow Memorial Lecture series and the Heinz Chapel 50th Anniversary.
    - Memorial Service for Russell M. Arnold - Heinz Chapel, July 13, 1976; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 11, Reel 97)
    - Dr. Adolf Grunbaum Reception, November 1978; 1 cassette_tape (Box 11, Cassette 127)
    - Dinner for Dr. Cheever, May 22, 1974; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 8, Reel 71)
    - Dinner in Honor of Leon Falk Jr. - Carnegie Music Hall, April 14, 1976; 1 reel-to-reel 7"; 1 cassette tape (Box 9, Item 77)
    - Greek Dinner Honoring Vice Chancellor Moye, December 7, 1978; 1 cassette_tape (Box 11, Cassette 129)
    - Program in Memory of William Hung, June 1, 1982; 1 cassette_tape (Box 24, Cassette 279)
    - Dinner Honoring Roger Ahlbrandt, December 16, 1982; 1 cassette_tape (Box 13, Cassette 152)
    - Samuel Lazerow Memorial Lecture - Conducted by Robert Lucky, 1989; 1 cassette_tape (Box 30, Cassette 355)
    - Samuel Lazerow Memorial Lecture - Conducted by Herbert Simon, October 22, 1991; 1 cassette_tape (Box 30, Cassette 356)
    - Samuel Lazerow Memorial Lecture - Conducted by Edward Tufle, October 28, 1992; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 30, Cassette 356)
    - Samuel Lazerow Memorial Lecture - Unknown Speaker, 1994; 1 cassette_tape (Box 30, Cassette 358)
    - Fred Rogers Reception, May 3, 1976; 1 cassette_tape (Box 11, Cassette 110)
    - Helen Poole Rush Reception, September 5, 1987; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 27, Cassette 286)
    - Heinz Chapel 50th Anniversary - Speeches by Wesley Posvar and Senator John Heinz, December 12, 1988; 1 cassette_tape (Box 28, Cassette 302)
    - 156th Anniversary- Speakers- Carl T. Rowan and Wesley W. Rowan, April 30, 1978
    - 175th Anniversary, September 18, 1962
- University History, 1958-1981; II.
  This subseries contains audio recordings pertaining to documenting the history of the University of Pittsburgh from 1958-1981. Highlights of this subseries include oral histories of the School of Information Sciences, the School of Social Work, and the R. Alberts University History Interviews.
  - R. Alberts' Interviews with University Officials, 1.
    - Interview with Ruth Crawford Mitchell - Conducted by R. Alberts, March 5, 1981 (Box 25, Cassette A1)
    - Interview with Ruth Crawford Mitchell - Part 2 - Conducted by R. Alberts, March 31, 1981 (Box 25, Cassette A2)
    - Interview with Carlton G. Ketchum - Conducted by R. Alberts, March 10, 1981 (Box 25, Cassette A3)
    - Interview with Carlton G. Ketchum - Conducted by R. Alberts, March 10, 1981 (Box 25, Cassette A4)
    - Interview with CV and Agnes Starrett - Conducted by R. Alberts, March 19, 1981 (Box 25, Cassette A5)
    - C.V. and Agnes Starrett Interview/Stein Interview (Side 2), March 19, 1981 (Box 25, Cassette A6)
    - Interview with Walter Hovey - Conducted by R. Alberts, April 7, 1981 (Box 25, Cassette A7)
    - Interview with Lawrence Irwin - Conducted by R. Alberts, April 16, 1981 (Box 25, Cassette A8)
    - Interview with William W. Booth - Conducted by R. Alberts, April 28, 1981 (Box 25, Cassette A9)
    - Interview with Edison Montgomery - Conducted by R. Alberts, April 23, 1981 (Box 25, Cassette A10)
    - Interview with Mrs. David Kurtzman - Conducted by R. Alberts, May 8, 1981 (Box 25, Cassette A11)
    - Interview with Walter Rome - Conducted by R. Alberts, May 12, 1981 (Box 25, Cassette A12)
    - Interview with Walter Rome - Conducted by R. Alberts, May 12, 1981 (Box 25, Cassette A13)
    - Interview with Robert Bailie - Conducted by R. Alberts, May 13, 1981 (Box 25, Cassette A14)
    - Interview with Robert Bailie - Conducted by R. Alberts, May 13, 1981 (Box 25, Cassette A15)
    - Interview with Charles Peake - Conducted by R. Alberts, May 27, 1981 (Box 25, Cassette A16)
    - Interview with Charles Peake - Conducted by R. Alberts, May 27, 1981 (Box 25, Cassette A17)
    - Interview with Frank Denton - Conducted by R. Alberts, September 7, 1981 (Box 25, Cassette A18)
    - Interview with Frank Denton - Conducted by R. Alberts, September 7, 1981 (Box 25, Cassette A19)
    - Interview with Edgar Cale - Conducted by R. Alberts, September 14, 1981 (Box 25, Cassette A20)
    - Interview with C.R. Wilson and George Fetterman - Conducted by R. Alberts, November 16, 1981 (Box 25, Cassette A21)
    - Interview with James Knox - Conducted by R. Alberts, December 9, 1981 (Box 25, Cassette A22)
    - Interview with James Knox - Conducted by R. Alberts, December 9, 1981 (Box 25, Cassette A23)
    - Interview with Helen Rush - Conducted by R. Alberts, March 29, 1981 (Box 25, Cassette A24)
    - Interview with Helen Rush - Conducted by R. Alberts, March 29, 1981 (Box 25, Cassette A25)
    - Interview with John Geise - Conducted by R. Alberts, undated (Box 25, Cassette A26)
    - Interview with John Geise - Conducted by R. Alberts, undated (Box 25, Cassette A27)
    - Interview with John Geise - Conducted by R. Alberts, undated (Box 25, Cassette A28)
    - Interview with A.C. Van Dusen - Conducted by R. Alberts, March 5, 1982 (Box 25, Cassette A29)
    - Interview with A.C. Van Dusen - Conducted by R. Alberts, March 5, 1982 (Box 25, Cassette A30)
    - Interview with Carlton G. Ketchum - Conducted by R. Alberts, April 3, 1982 (Box 25, Cassette A31)
    - Interview with Carlton G. Ketchum - Conducted by R. Alberts, April 9, 1982 (Box 25, Cassette A32)
    - Interview with John Funari - Conducted by R. Alberts, November 2, 1982 (Box 25, Cassette A33)
    - Interview with Wesley Wentz Posvar - Conducted by R. Alberts, August 8, 1983 (Box 25, Cassette A34)
    - Interview with Wesley Wentz Posvar - Conducted by R. Alberts, August 8, 1983 (Box 25, Cassette A35)
    - Interview with Frank Carver - Conducted by R. Alberts, July 1, 1981 (Box 26, Cassette A36)
    - Interview with Frank Carver/William Tracy - Conducted R. Alberts, July 1 and July 16, 1981 (Box 26, Cassette A37)
    - Interview with William Tacey/Gwilym Price - Conducted by R. Alberts, August 4, 1981 (Box 26, Cassette A38)
    - Interview with Gwilym Price - Conducted by R. Alberts, August 4, 1981 (Box 26, Cassette A39)
    - Interview with Walter Evert - Conducted by R. Alberts, July 10, 1981 (Box 26, Cassette A40)
    - Interview with William Rea - Conducted by R. Alberts, November 23, 1981 (Box 26, Cassette A41)
  - School of Information Sciences Oral History - Conducted by the Charles Babbage Institute, 1986-2000; 2.
    - Interview with Anthony Debons - Conducted by William Aspray, May 3, 1997; 4 cassette_tapes (Box 30, Cassette 359)
    - Interview with Anthony Debons - Conducted by William Aspray, September 16, 1999; 1 cassette_tape (Box 30, Cassette 360)
    - Interview with Sara Fine - Conducted by William Aspray, June 17, 1999; 1 cassette_tape (Box 30, Cassette 361)
    - Interview with Margaret Kimmel - Conducted by William Aspray, June 4, 1999; 1 cassette_tape (Box 30, Cassette 363)
    - Interview with James G. Williams - Conducted by William Aspray, January 18, 2000; 1 cassette_tape (Box 30, Cassette 363)
    - Interview with Toni Carbo - Conducted by William Aspray, December 22, 1999; 1 cassette_tape (Box 30, Cassette 364)
    - Interview with Ellen G. Detlefsen - Conducted by William Aspray, May 24, 1999; 1 cassette_tape (Box 30, Cassette 365)
    - Interview with Donald Shorey - Conducted by William Aspray, May 4, 1997; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 30, Cassette 366)
    - Interview with Allen Kent - Conducted by William Aspray, May 20, 1997; 1 cassette_tape (Box 30, Cassette 367)
    - Interview with E.J. Josey - Conducted by William Aspray, July 14, 1999; 1 cassette_tape (Box 30, Cassette 368)
    - Interview with Wendell Wray - Conducted by William Aspray, July 28, 1999; 1 cassette_tape (Box 30, Cassette 369)
    - Interview with Allen Kent - Conducted by William Aspray, July 28, 1999; 1 cassette_tape (Box 30, Cassette 370)
    - Interview with William Nasri - Conducted by William Aspray, July 15, 1999; 1 cassette_tape (Box 30, Cassette 371)
    - Interview with Dr. Jerry Saye - Conducted by William Aspray, November 11, 1988; 1 cassette_tape (Box 30, Cassette 373)
    - Interview with Dr. Selma Burke - Conducted by William Aspray, November 11, 1988; 1 cassette_tape (Box 30, Cassette 374)
  - Other, 3.
    - Interview with George Swetnam - "History of Pittsburgh", 1958; 1 reel-to-reel 2 cassettes (Box 6, Reel 46)
    - Interview with Stanton Balfour - "Pittsburgh--Through 200 Years", undated; 1 reel-to-reel 1 User Cassette/2 Cassettes (Box 6, Reel 50)
    - John Geise - Pitt Oral History, 1972; 1 reel-to-reel 2 cassettes (Box 12, Cassette 141)
    - History of the University, 1963; 5 reel-to-reel Reels (Labelled A-D) (Box 19, Reel 209)
    - The Idea of Community at the University of Pittsburgh/The Prospects of a Learning Society/What's Wrong with the University? - Conducted by Rosemary Park and Robert Hutchins, undated; 3 reel-to-reel (Box 20, Reel 212)
    - The Voice of America at Pitt, undated; 2 reel-to-reel (Labelled A-B) (Box 20, Reel 213)
    - The American Experience - The University of Pittsburgh - Conducted by Lester Thurow, April 10, 1986; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 29, Cassette 348)
- Administration, 1950-2000; III.
  This series contains audio recordings that focus on the administration and functions of the University of Pittsburgh faculty and staff from 1950-2000. Included in this series are various staff meetings, faculty speeches, and planning committees' meetings pertaining to the administration of the University. Highlights of the series include speeches by both University Chancellors Edward Litchfield and Wesley Posvar.
  - Staff Meetings, 1956-1997; 1.
    This subseries contains 35 audio recordings of staff meetings at the University of Pittsburgh from 1956-1997. Included are faculty orientations, advisory committees, and Deans' meetings at Pitt and its branch campuses. Highlights include Chancellor Edward H. Litchfield's first speech to the faculty.
    - All Day Deans' Meeting - Speech by Wesley Posvar, December 21, 1983; 4 cassette_tapes (Box 14, Cassette 164)
    - Speech at His First Faculty Meeting - Chancellor Edward H. Litchfield, March 26, 1956; 2 reel-to-reel 7"; 1 cassette tape (Box 2, Item 4)
    - Meeting of Deans/Directors/Chairman, June 29, 1972; 1 cassette_tape (Box 11, Cassette 100)
    - Deans, Directors Meetings, April 16, 1975; 1 cassette_tape (Box 11, Cassette 108)
    - Deans' Meeting at Johnstown, June 4, 1986; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 24, Cassette 270)
    - Deans' Meeting - U.PARC, December 17, 1987; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 28, Cassette 297)
    - Administrators Meeting Held in Greesnburg, June 1987; 5 cassette_tapes (Box 27, Cassette 287)
    - Staff Advisory Committee on Policy (Library), December 12, 1973; 1 cassette_tape (Box 10, Cassette 81)
    - Staff Advisory Committee on Policy (Library), June 20, 1973; 1 cassette_tape (Box 10, Cassette 80)
    - Staff Advisory Committee on Policy (Library), January 17, 1973; 1 cassette_tape (Box 10, Cassette 82)
    - Staff Advisory Committee on Policy (Library), March 21, 1973; 1 cassette_tape (Box 10, Cassette 85)
    - Staff Advisory Committee on Policy (Library), March 28, 1973; 1 cassette_tape (Box 10, Cassette 86)